# **Ethan Truong**

#### Game Developer | Game Designer



Scarborough, ON



bangatruong@gmail.com

libiki123.github.io/ethan-truong github.com/libiki123 linkedin.com/in/ethan-truong-abc123



### Profile

A Game developer with a wide range of programming skills and experiences in multiple platforms. A quick learner, self driven, problem solver and hard working. An exceptional student with a well-respected GPA, a team player with great leadership skills. I'm passionate about game and spent my free time learning new tools, recreating some of my favourite games using the Unity/Unreal Engine or joining game Jams, you can check out some of my previous projects on my website (Link: libiki123.github.io/ethan-truong).

# Work Experience

**Marion Surgical** 

Toronto, ON

Game Developer | Full-time

June 2021 – present

- Develop a VR game In Unreal Engine using C++ & Blueprint
- Design, suggest ideas and work with the client to turn his vision into a playable Demo
- Writing maintainable and easy to understand code
- Create simple VFX and shader for the game prototype
- Work independently, solve problems through documentation or help from the game dev community
- Working with other team to developer other aspects/ features of the game
- Create simple animations/models using Blender

**CaseWare International** 

Automation Test Developer | Co-op

September 2019 – May 2020

- Developed fully automated tests that are maintaining current features or find out bugs when new features deployed using Java & C#
- Understanding and working with Agile workflow (Scrum and Kanban)
- Create/add/refactor testing SDK library used to communicate with company cloud server
- Contributed in designing UI for a new multi-sever cloud feature
- Collaborated with different team depend on the project
- Used Jenkin to run and maintain tests

## Projects

VR car mechanic simulator & boxing (UE4) – Individual project (2021/07 - present)

A project I start working on recently, It VR simulator that allow you to screw/unscrew parts of a car Link: Currently Private

**Getting Over it – But is it? (Unity) – Individual project (2021/05)** 

This is my submission for the 2021 CGX Grad Jam – Game Jam

Link: https://github.com/libiki123/Getting Over It But Is It

AR Arcade racing (Unity) – Individual project (2021/06)

An Arcade racing build using the unity AR foundation – cross platform mobile game

Link: <a href="https://github.com/libiki123/AR">https://github.com/libiki123/AR</a> Racing

**2D platformer (Unity) –** Individual project (2021/04 – present)

A 2D platformer using state movement and Finite State Machine for enemy AI

Link: https://github.com/libiki123/2D Platformer - In progress

Mobile games Replica (Unity) – Individual project (2021/05)

Replica of some the famous mobile games

Link: Fruit Ninja Replica | Line Rider Replica | Angry Birds Replica | Cut The Rope Replica

**Dungeon and level Generator (Unity)** – Individual project (2021/05)

An advance procedural level and dungeon generator

Link: https://github.com/libiki123/Dungeon And Level Generator



### Education

Seneca College

Computer programming and Analysis 3.9 GPA

North York, ON January 2018 - August 2020



#### **Game Development**

- Programming/Languages: C#, C++
- Experiences: Design/create small games using Unity and Unreal Engine

#### **Mobile Application Development**

- <u>Programming/Languages</u>: **Objective-C, Swift, Java, Kotlin**
- Experiences: Design/create small apps using Xcode/Android studio. Able to use external frameworks, APIs (Cocoapod, Carthage, ...). Familiar with mobile database (SQLite, Core Data, Firebase ...)

#### **Software Development**

- Programming/Languages: C, C++, Java
- Experiences: Design small size program, simple algorithms

#### Web Development

- Programming/Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, MySQL, Typescript
- Framework: Angular, Vue, React
- Experience: Create simple websites in both back/front-end.

#### Database

- Programming/Languages: SQL
- Databases Management: Oracle 8.x/9.x, SQL Server